//bronze: 5 questions displaying corect and incorrect
//silver: questions rotate one at a time
//gold: scores are tracked, css complete

/*Hard code questions worked. Need Object literal to
create dynamic questions. Use */

//Global variables
let QUIZ_QA;
let QUESTION_ANSWER;
var bestTime = localStorage.getItem("bestTime", bestTime)
var userName = localStorage.getItem("userName", userName)
var tickTock;
var userTime;

// .ready prevents functions from running until after html loads
$(document).ready(function(){
  $(".quiz").hide();
  if (userName != null) {
    $(".bestTime").html(userName + " completed the quiz in " + bestTime + " seconds.")
  };
  //used to create the timer
  tickTock = 0
  var timeCounter = function(){
    tickTock++
    $(".scoreKeeper").html("Timer: " + tickTock)
  };

  $(".startButton").click(function(){
    $(".quiz").show();
    userTime = setInterval(timeCounter, 1000)
  });

  //snake case
  QUESTION_ANSWER = [
    {question: "Where is the largest wind turbine in the world?   [UK or Denmark]", answer: "UK", hint: "It's no longer the Dutch. A single revolution of the 8MW turbine blade, can power one house for 29 hours."},
    {question: "Which sector produces more CO2? a: Transportation or b: Electricity and Heat Production   [a/b]", answer: "b", hint: "It's not cars"},
    {question: "Does the burning of fossil fuels produce CO2 and Acid Rain?   [yes/no]", answer: "yes", hint: "It's the worst"},
    {question: "___ is heat from within the earth which can be used to heat buildings or generate electricity.   [geothermal energy/nuclear energy]", answer: "geothermal energy", hint: "Think dirty"},
    {question: "The energy saved by recycling one aluminium drink can is enough to run a TV for how many minutes?   [30, 60, 180, 200]", answer: "180", hint: "Not 1 or 2 hours, but... "},
    {question: "The amount of energy poured onto the Earth by the Sun every 15 minutes is equivalent to what? The entire world's enery for a ____.   [hour,day, month, year]", answer: "year", hint: "A really long time"}
    //additional questions can be added
    // {question: "what is g", answer: "g", hint: "alphabet g"},
    // {question: "what is h", answer: "h", hint: "alphabet h"},
    // {question: "what is i", answer: "i", hint: "alphabet i"},
    // {question: "what is j", answer: "j", hint: "alphabet j"}
  ]
  i = 0
  $(".question").html("<span>" + QUESTION_ANSWER[i].question + "</span>")
  $(".questionNum").html("Question: " + (i + 1) + " of 6")
  $(".nextQuestion").hide()

  $(".hintButton").on("click", function(){
    $(".questionHint").html(QUESTION_ANSWER[i].hint)
  });
  $(".restartQuiz").on("click", function(){
    location.reload();
  })

  //e prevents page from refreshing
  QUIZ_QA = $(".answerButton").on("click", function(e){
    e.preventDefault();
    if ($(".inputField").val() === QUESTION_ANSWER[i].answer) {
      $(".answer").html("Correct")
      $(".answerButton").hide()
      i += 1
      $(".nextQuestion").show()
      $(".scoreKeeper").html()
      if ($(".inputField").val() === QUESTION_ANSWER[QUESTION_ANSWER.length - 1].answer) {
        //stores timer and user name in local storage
        bestTime = tickTock.toString()
        localStorage.setItem("bestTime", bestTime)
        clearInterval(userTime)
        userName = prompt("You're an Energy Champ! Please enter your name to show off your time.")
        localStorage.setItem("userName", userName)
      }
      $(".nextQuestion").on("click", function() {
        $(".question").html(QUESTION_ANSWER[i].question)
        $(".questionNum").html("Question Number: " + (i + 1))
        $(".inputField").val("")
        $(".answerButton").show()
        $(".nextQuestion").hide()
      })
    } else {
      $(".answer").html("Incorrect, Please try again")
    }
  });

});
